So here's another trick that will help us move a point closer to a line,
这是另一个技巧 可以帮助我们让某个点更加接近直线
and it's very similar to the absolute trick but it has a little bit of extra gravy.
这与绝对值技巧非常类似 不过有些特别之处
It's based on this premise.
它有个前提
If we have a point that is close to a line,
如果我们这个点靠近直线
then this distance is small and we want to move the line very little.
距离较小 我们会小幅移动直线
But if the point is far from the line,
但是如果这个点远离直线
then want to move the line a lot more.
我们可以大幅移动直线
The absolute trick that we learned previously does
我们之前学过的绝对值技巧
not have this property because if we remember
不具有这个属性 因为如果还记得的话
the absolute trick adds alpha to the y-intercept w_2 and p times alpha to the slope w_1.
绝对值技巧将 α 加到 y 轴截距 W2 中 p 乘以 α 加到斜率 W1 中
This has nothing to do with how far the point is from the line,
这与点到直线的距离无关
since P is just a horizontal distance.
因为 p 只是水平距离
So let's just add the vertical distance into this formula.
所以现在我们把垂直距离加到这个公式中
Let's look at this vertical distance between the point and the line.
我们来看一下 这是点到直线的垂直距离
The point over the line has coordinates say,( p,q').
距离为 q 减去 y
This distance is then q minus q' because q' is
因为 y 是直线的值
the value at the line and q is the value of the y coordinate at the point.
q 是这个点的纵坐标值
So what we do here is very simple.
所以我们这里要做的很简单
We just take this q minus q' and multiply it into
我们用这个 q 减去 y 的结果乘以
what we're adding to both the y-intercept and to the slope.
我们加入 y 轴截距和斜率的值
This will again make the line go up by a bit and rotate in
这样可以再让直线向上移动一点
this direction except that now if the point is far from or close to the line,
沿着方向旋转一些 如果这个点距离直线过远或很近
the amount the line moves will be
直线移动的数量会受到影响
affected and here's our new equation with a factor of q minus q'.
因此我们在新的方程中包含一个因数  q - y
Notice that here we get something for free.
N注意下这里 我们很容易得到了想要的东西
If the point is underneath the line instead of over the line,
如果这个点在直线的下方 而不是上方
then q minus q' is actually a negative value and if this is the case then we're
那么 q - y 实际上是负数 如果是这种情况
subtracting something from the slope thus rotating the line in this direction instead,
我们在斜率中减去某个数 然后沿着这个方向旋转直线
still towards the point.
而不是向这个点旋转
So this trick also takes care of points that are under
所以这个技巧也考虑到点位于直线下方的情况
the line and we don't have to have two rules like we had on the absolute trick.
我们可以不用像绝对值技巧一样使用两个规则
We just have one same rule for both.
可以一石二鸟
Again, let's clarify this with an example.
我们再通过例子来详细了解下
In this example over here,
在这个例子中
we have the point (5,15) and notice that
这个点坐标为 (5,15)
this distance is going to be two because the line goes
注意此处距离为 2
through the (5,13) as two times five plus three is 13.
因为 2*5+3 等于 13 所以直线上的这个点为 (5,13)
Now to change things a bit,
现在稍微改变一下
we'll use zero point 0.01 as the learning rate.
我们设学习率为 0.01
So the absolute trick would be adding 0.01 to the y-intercept and 0.05 to the slope.
利用绝对值技巧 我们在 y 轴截距加 0.01 在斜率加 0.05
But now as our neutral access,
但是现在根据新技巧
we multiply the two numbers two adding to the slope and the y-intercept by two;
我们用加在斜率和 y 轴截距的两个数字乘以 2
which means we're adding 0.12 to the slope and 0.02 to the y-intercept.
也就是说我们在斜率加 0.1 在 y 轴截距加 0.02
So the equation of our new line is y equals 2.1_x plus 3.02.
所以我们的新方程为 y = 2.1x + 3.02
Notice that that line is going to be closer to the point.
这条直线更加靠近这个点
So that's it. That's the square trick.
就是这样 这叫做平方技巧